CELERINO HERRERA

WHO AM I

.Net Developer with 15 years working with C# .Net for desktop and web applications. I've had the opportunity to work for many different business types: Accounting, Healthcare, Point of Sales, government, security, warehouses, etc.

I am a team player. I try to have **constant communication** with testers or product owners. When it's about challenges, I reach <u>my peers</u> before wearing my detective hat.

Agile and Scrum methodologies have been common for me since 10 years ago.

I have worked doing bug fixing for legacy code and building solutions in C# Javascript SQL Server, most of the time, DTS Packages in SSIS. Java, Visual Foxpro; VBScript for MSOffice and MSAccess 2003-2010, VB.Net and several reporting tools such as Reporting Services (as server and local mode), Devexpress, Crystal Reports, and others. Code reviews with GITS, ReviewBoard, and experience with continuous delivery with JetBrains-TeamCity and VSTS.

EXPERIENCE

SR. DEVELOPER, FREELANCE

July - 2018 - Current

BairesDev -

Home office developer. Performing bug fixing tasks over legacy code in C#, devexpress reports, and SQL server.

Also, for BairesDev I have performed over a hundred technical interviews for new members

July 2017- 2018

On-site developer for Contpaq, a company with one of the most successful accounting software in México. C# developer working with Lucene.Net, SQL Server. I loved this job, but had to leave to experience home office development.

SR. DEVELOPER, TCS - TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES, GUADALAJARA

May 2014 - 2017

TCS is an outsourcing company in which I've participated as Sr. Developer. There I also performed a lot of coaching activities for new members (growing the team from 2 to 12 resources) and also as an interviewer for more than 30 candidates for a HealthCare company.

Health care project:

Maintenance to legacy code in Javascript, Typescript, AngularJS, C#.

Front end development in AngularJS/Typescript. HTML/CSS with MVC and Restful API on backend.

Creation of Unit Tests for C# in NUnit framework.

Analysis of user activities related to Healthcare sectors: practices, pharmacies, nurses, patients, diagnostics.

Release meetings with over 60+ at Dallas, Tx every quarter, and Sprint Planings. every two weeks.

SR. DEVELOPER, TIEMPO DEVELOPMENT, HERMOSILLO

May 2010 - 2014

Tiempo Development is an outsourcing company. There I've worked on these projects.

ATARetail:

Maintenance to legacy code for the biggest system of ATARetail, made in MSAccess 2003 (VBScript). As they have SQL Server as a data source, it was easy to suggest, design and implement the new features requested with MVC 4. Bootstrap and Codefirst was the option chosen for the frontend.

Tools used:

C#, MS Visual Studio 2012, MS Access 2003, MS Access 2010, SQL Server, IIS Server management, Visual Source Safe, TFS.

Profit Keeper:

Maintenance to ASP.Net systems in VB.Net. New modules were added using the exact same code conventions as the current code.

Tools used:

VB.Net, MS Visual Studio 2008, Visual Source Safe 6.

Tripwire:

Creation of regular expressions for the parser of TripWire Log Center. Bug fixing for the backend of TLC. In charge of analysis to make the system FIPS Compliant, identifying algorithms used inside the application and in third-party tools and making replacing suggestions or modifications to the source code. The development process was reproducing the defect, confirming it with a tester, code the fix, asking for code review, and committing the code; a specific build was made for the tester.

Tools used:

C#, MS Visual Studio 2010, VistaDB, TeamCity, ReviewBoard, Version One, DeployLX (licensing), Apache Lucene.Net (for searching inside file system), NUnit.

SR. DEVELOPER, BUFETE DE TECNOLOGÍA Y SOLUCIONES AVANZADAS [BTS], MEXICALI

Jun 2007 - May 2010

BTS is a company focused to fulfill government needs. I have worked with systems running in three dependencies: Ministerio Público, Procuraduría de Justicia and Secretaría de Seguridad (Police).

Frontend and Backend developer for desktop application. Following use cases and architecture specifications as a guide. Release master for ClickOnce distribution.

Implementation in site for three dependencies of the Honduras government. .

- C# Development for desktop applications that consume all data from datasets provided by Web Services (SOA).
- Design Patterns Experience (Enterprise Library Model View Presenter).
- Asp.Net developer (portal for Reporting Services reports).
- Support Architecture design for asp.net based application for the government of Puebla, México.

Tools used:

MS Visio, MS Infopath, MS Visual Studio 2005 and 2008, SqlServer Management Studio 2005, Oracle Sql Developer, Devtrack.

DEVELOPER, EQUIPOS Y SISTEMAS [EYS], MEXICALI

Sep 2005 – Dec 2006

Use of web services for synchronization of points of sales between stores in order to have real-time queries of Inventory and Sales Reports (this was fully configurable for any kind of ODBC data you wanted to synchronize).

• Improve Visual Fox-Pro Applications as architect and developer. C# architect and developer for new system EysCommercia.Net (still active).

- ASP.Net developer for Baja California's government Health care dependency "Seguro Popular"
- Develop login controls for use of biometrics instruments (voice recognition and digital fingerprints).

Tools used:

Crystal Reports, Visual Studio 2003 and 2005, SqlServer Management Studio 2005, Visual FoxPro 9.

JR. DEVELOPER, URBI DESARROLLOS URBANOS [URBI], MEXICALI

6 month school practices.

Java Desktop Developer. Developed servlets for offline use with MS Office.

Research of PENTAHO reports with MDX query language.

Tools used:

TOAD for Oracle, Oracle Development Studio, Dream Weaver for JSP. NetBeans.

BS in Computing Engineering, Universidad Autónoma de Baja California (UABC) 2003-2008.

EDUCATION

UABC - MEXICALI - BS COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2003-2008

Microsoft Certified Professional Program.

Microsoft Exam T 536 (expired).

Tijuana, México Ago – 2009

CCNA, **Cisco Academy**. Caborca, México.

Jan 2001.

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

ENGLISH: Professional working proficiency